[JAEGERIST 83A]
Oliver! You okay? I got you!
[HANGE] That's it.
The last of our pursuers, Levi.
[HANGE]
Everyone got turned into Titans.
You're the only one
who survived.
Likely for the same
reason you lived
through a Thunder Spear blast
at point-blank range.
You Ackermanns aren't
built like the rest of us.
[HANGE] We're still here,
but what do we do?
There's no way the two of us
can stop Zeke by ourselves.
It's up to Armin and
Commander Pyxis now.
Eren might be planning to turn
on Zeke and hijack the Founder.
But thanks to
Zeke's tainted wine,
the Jaegerists would
retain control of the island,
so even if Eren wins,
we'll be on the run
for the rest of our lives.
That's it. Guess it's
really my turn, huh.
Ever since this started,
I've just been trying
to do what I thought was right.
And after everything
that's happened,
it could land me in a cell.
Or maybe you and I
can just camp out here
in the sticks forever.
Right, Levi?
[Gasps] He wouldn't.
The whole world?
How can he not see that-- Levi!
[LEVI]
What happened?
Where is that
hairy sack of shit?
[HANGE]
No need to get up.
Zeke's long gone,
the Jaegerists found him
after hearing the explosion.
They took off for
Shiganshina half a day ago.
What happened?
How did he break free?
It was my fault.
I screwed up.
Had him rigged to blow
if he tried to
break his restraints.
I didn't think he'd do it.
I was wrong and he got away.
Worrying about it
won't help us now.
We can't do anything but--
[LEVI] Run and hide?
If we do, what'll that get us?
[Gasp] Fair question.
You must have been lying there
listening to me talk
to myself for a while.
What's with your
little project, there?
That for me?
Gonna pull me around
with a horse?
Yeah, that sounds like you.
There's no way
in hell you're gonna
be staying out of the action.
That's right, you know
me far too well.
Can't help myself.
[LEVI] I'm after one thing now.
My goal is to take Zeke's head.
Theo Magath. Pieck Finger.
Looks like our
interests are aligned.
[MAGATH] Levi Ackermann,
the man who went
toe-to-toe with one of
the Nine all on his own.
Not sure how you plan on
dodging a bullet,
given the shape you're in.
I couldn't dodge
a punch right now,
and yet, I still
chose to come here
and put myself at your mercy.
Shoot me, or hear me out.
The choice is yours.
Well, hell. I can always
shoot you later.
If you two are
planning to kill Zeke,
does that mean you already
know where to find him?
He'll be with the Founder.
The fact that this is
happening indicates
Zeke's royal blood
is in contact with Eren,
or rather, the Founding Titan,
I should say.
I never would've guessed
that you would be
this knowledgeable
about Titans, Hange.
You know more
than Marley's guys.
I don't suppose you've laid eyes
on the Founding Titan yourself?
I know that the thing
is humongous.
So big that it seems
like nothing would
ever be able to slow it down.
But we've gotta try.
Let's give ourselves
the best possible chance.
Our only option now is to
join forces. So what do you say?
♪ Opening Song ♪
[CONNY]
I still don't know how I'll
actually get Mom to eat Falco.
Just force him into her mouth?
[CONNY] But if he gets
hurt in the process
and figures out that he can
turn Titan, then that's it.
I can't screw it up.
I need to come up with
a plan. A real one.
[CONNY]
He's such a good kid.
He's camping out here
in the woods
without a single complaint,
and he has every
reason to doubt me.
[CONNY]
But he trusts me with his life.
Dammit!
Sasha. Would you have understood
what I'm about to do?
[FALCO] Sir? I thought you were
taking me to a hospital,
but this is an
abandoned village.
[CONNY] Right. There's just
something interesting here.
Thought you might
like to see it.
[FALCO]
Is this Ragako Village?
[CONNY gasps]
You've heard of it before?
How'd you know?
'Cause you mentioned it.
I accidentally heard you
talking to yourself last night.
And that name, "Sasha."
You were talking about
one of the other soldiers.
She was the one
Gabi shot, right?
The whole time,
you've known exactly who I was,
yet you acted like you didn't
'til you'd gotten me out here.
Why do all this?
Why would you go to
that much effort?
For revenge?
Hardly.
Soldiers get killed
in the heat of battle.
I know that.
[Gasps]
[CONNY]
It's been lying here for years.
Never even budged.
It's not a threat to us.
Why is it here?
And why show me?
What are you gonna
do with me now?
[CONNY gasps]
Yeah, guess I never
mentioned that.
Think you could help me
brush its teeth?
It's a pretty rare opportunity.
Wouldn't wanna pass it up.
Huh?
But first, we're gonna
have to climb up onto
that rafter for a better angle.
The ladder is solid
and I'm not gonna
let you fall or anything.
So. Let's get to it!
Sounds good.
[GABI]
Falco! Get away from him now!
Gabi?
He brought you out here because
he wants to feed you
to that Titan!
Please stop.
Don't do it, Conny!
Get back! Don't come any closer!
[Gasps]
[ARMIN]
Conny!
Just shut up!
I don't wanna hear it!
Don't even bother talking to me,
'cause there's no way
I'm gonna listen!
You're gonna say I should
give up on saving my Mom.
'Cause his life is
more important than hers.
And you're smart,
so you might be right.
But I'm way too much
of an idiot to care!
[GABI] Falco, you have to use
the power of the Jaw Titan!
Use the power of the Jaw? What?
But what about Mr. Galliard?
Not Falco. He's innocent!
Let him go!
Gabi, please forgive
Conny for this, okay?
[Gasps]
Hey! Didn't you hear me
say to stay back?
[Gasps]
[CONNY] Wait. What are you
doing up there?
Hey! Answer the
damn question, Armin!
Why? You just told me that
you weren't gonna listen!
So I won't answer.
I'll just let my actions
speak instead.
Oh, Colt.
[CONNY] If I hadn't saved you,
what were you gonna do?
[ARMIN] The same thing
you were gonna do.
Make your mom human again.
You also would've made her into
the inheritor of the Colossal.
There would've been nothing
ahead of her but more pain.
It shouldn't take a genius
to figure that much out.
[CONNY]
When she saw me off,
she told me to become a great
soldier--everyone's protector.
But right in front of her eyes,
my friend almost died trying to
stop me from murdering a kid.
Guess that's the kind of soldier
I turned out to be. Pathetic.
I'm not any better.
I'll never come close to
filling the Commander's shoes.
Look, Armin.
I wanna try and become
the kind of soldier
my mom would be proud of.
So let's do it.
There's a whole world of people
that need saving right now.
[MIKASA]
There you are.
[LOUISE]
I'm glad to see you.
Have you been looking because
you were worried
I didn't make it?
Or is it because you
wanted your scarf back?
[MIKASA]
I was pretty sure you'd have it.
I'm sorry for taking it.
I just... I felt like
maybe it could
bring me a bit closer to you.
There's shrapnel from a Thunder
Spear deep in my stomach.
The doctors can't get it out.
For one hundred years,
we've been imprisoned
on this island,
but Eren's giving our people
a world where we can be free.
I wish I could see it.
We spoke before,
just a short conversation
when I was bringing his food.
We were talking about you.
[LOUISE]
When the scarf came up,
he said he wanted
to throw it out.
And so, if it was just
gonna get tossed,
I figured it wouldn't
hurt anything if I--
[MIKASA]
Give it back.
[LOUISE] I became a soldier
because I admired you.
And I'll die with no regrets.
I pledged my heart and soul,
just like you.
I followed in your footsteps
as best I could
and gave my life to the cause.
[PARADIS MAN 83A] The last Wall
Titans are finally marching off.
[PARADIS MAN 83B]
Yeah. It'll be nice to have
a little bit of quiet again.
[PARADIS MAN 83A]
I don't mind the rumbling.
To me, it sounds like
the bells of freedom.
[FLOCH] For the past century,
our Eldian Empire has
suffered persecution at the
hands of the outside world.
That ends now!
At this moment,
we're finally free!
Thanks to our liberator, Eren,
and all the efforts of
my fellow Jaegerists,
our people have
achieved victory!
[JAEGERISTS cheer]
So. What are you thinking?
You know the Jaegerists have
a place for you at the top.
Are you gonna join them
and start calling the shots?
Think I'll pass on that.
Guess whatever
you're worried about
doesn't really bother Jean.
Our hearts and souls,
to the cause!
[JAEGERISTS] Our hearts
and souls, to the cause!
[FLOCH] Our hearts and souls,
to the cause!
[JAEGERISTS] Our hearts
and souls, to the cause!
[FLOCH] Our hearts and souls,
to the cause!
[PARADIS MEN] Our hearts
and souls, to the cause!
[PARADIS MAN 83D]
Glory to the Jaegerists!
[PARADIS MAN 83E] Our hearts
and souls, to the cause!
[PARADIS MAN 83F]
To Eren, liberator of Eldia!
I think we should go and
get Reiner as soon as possible.
He shouldn't even be waking up
for a few more days,
so there's no hurry.
Are we sure taking this
detour was a good idea?
We were gonna have to
eat eventually, right?
[CONNY]
So, you think it's true, Armin?
[ARMIN] Mm-hm. If all
Titan hardening came undone
when the walls fell,
then there's no reason to think
that wouldn't include Annie's--
[ANNIE coughs]
[ARMIN]
Wha-- Annie?
[ALL gasp]
[CONNY laughs]
Look at that.
Annie was stuffing
her face with pie! [Laughs]
Come on, Conny, that's enough.
She had half that
slice in her mouth!
Yeah, but she hasn't had
a bite in four years!
[HITCH] Sorry! The line
for pie was ridiculous.
Right, never mind, then.
[ANNIE]
Dear Hitch.
I happened across
Armin and Conny,
and I decided it was
best if I joined them.
So, I'm off.
Sorry for all the trouble.
Thank you for keeping me company
these past four years.
Goodbye. Sincerely,
your gloomy roommate.
Jeez, Annie.
You expect me to eat
this whole pie by myself?
[FLOCH] Comrades of the Empire,
thank you for joining me!
We are gathered here
for the execution
of these two Volunteers.
They've both admitted to
opposing the Eldian Empire!
And in removing these disloyal
elements from our midst,
we're taking our
first step towards
realizing Eren's dream
of world domination--
by declaring Eldia's
uncontested rule over Paradis!
[JAEGERISTS cheer]
[FLOCH]
This criminal is Yelena.
She took up arms
and opposed Marley.
She lived among us
and fought at our side,
but she did not fight for us!
Her loyalty was to Zeke,
and Zeke alone!
She sought to turn the
Founder's power against us
and wipe the Eldian
people from the earth!
She was nothing but another
filthy Marleyan from the start!
Thankfully, Eren was
able to defeat Zeke
and put an end to
his traitorous plot.
Nonetheless, this criminal
served as Zeke's puppet
every step of the way!
[JAEGERIST 83D]
Marleyan whore!
[JAEGERIST 83E]
Send her to hell!
Well, Yelena?
Any last words
you'd like to share?
[YELENA]
Would you get it over with?
[JAEGERISTS yelling]
Kill her now! Do it!
Put her down!
[JAEGERISTS] Shoot her!
Shoot her! Shoot her! Shoot her!
It isn't time yet!
[JAEGERISTS chattering]
[FLOCH]
This criminal is Onyankopon.
He used to be
a steadfast ally of Eldia.
And he had no knowledge of
Zeke's euthanization plan.
That said, when offered
the privilege of citizenship
in the reborn Eldian Empire,
he claimed he would rather die!
It's still not too late
for you to reconsider.
[Laughs]
I joined up with
the Volunteers because
I wanted to liberate my own
homeland from Marleyan rule.
And yes, I wanted to help
your people as well!
But how are you repaying my help
now that you've won?
My whole country's
gonna be destroyed.
Eren's gonna kill
everybody I care for, right?
And I get to live out
my life here with your
sad little gang of
xenophobic shitheads? [Laughs]
If living on means
sucking up to you guys,
I'm more than ready to die!
Everybody on this island had
their lives turned upside down
by sudden acts of
indiscriminate mass murder!
So how is it not a single
one of you understands?
Talk some sense
into 'em, Jean! Please!
[Gasps]
[Gunshots]
Hey!
Sorry about that.
It pulled right.
What do you mean?
Don't screw with me, Jean.
[JAEGERISTS gasp]
[BOTH gasp]
[JEAN]
Floch!
[JAEGERIST 83N]
That was the Cart Titan!
[JAEGERIST 83O]
They got away!
[JAEGERIST 83P]
It ate Jean!
[JAEGERIST 83Q]
And Yelena!
Hey. Someone find Mikasa!
She can take out the Cart.
Hold on. Was she even here?
Where's Mikasa?
You heard that, right?
He said he'd signal us
with four gunshots.
Jean must be ready to
kick off the next phase.
We grabbed enough
food and munitions
to keep us going for a while.
All eyes should be fixed on
the other side of the fort
for at least a few minutes.
Let's roll out!
[ANNIE]
Somebody spotted us!
What are we gonna do now, Armin?
No choice but to keep moving.
Faster, Mikasa!
[JEAN retching]
That's the last damn time
I get in a Titan's mouth.
[HANGE] The Cart's
supposed to be able to
stay in Titan form for
months at a time, right?
Don't you ever brush your teeth?
You shouldn't ask such things.
I'm a lady, remember?
Now you're on our side?
When'd you join up with Marley?
It was last night.
But why'd you do it?
I don't get it.
You could have had
a life of luxury.
The Jaegerists would have given
you anything you asked them for.
You're right. If I had
any sense at all,
I'd be sitting in my room with
my ears plugged right now.
But no. Then that
burning pile of bones
would've haunted me
for the rest of my life.
Jean. I have no idea
what you're talking about,
but you have my thanks.
Wash up, you smell
like Titan breath.
Why me? After everything.
[HANGE] We needed to
borrow the Cart's power
to make this plan work.
You were just part of the deal.
For some reason, they insisted
that we take you alive.
[Groans]
[ANNIE]
Wake up.
Annie?
[GABI]
Whoa, take it easy, Reiner!
[FALCO] Don't worry, it's okay.
We're all on the same side now.
[CONNY]
There's not much time. Let's go.
Go where?
To end this and save the world.
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR] Strangers become
enemies in the chaos of war.
We learn to hurt, kill,
and despise each other,
but what do we see
through the campfire's flame?
Next episode:
"Night of the End."